Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Senior Prize Essays
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- History senior essay prize winners, 1990-2003; Series I
  - 2002-2003
    - Gandhi, Sushma. "Undocumented Immigration from Tlaxcala, Mexico to New Haven, CT: A History of Choices Made by Policy-makers and People" Andrew D. White Prize - Rest of the World (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - Heller, Andrew. ""Mal-Conformations of Mr. Adams' Mind": Dialects of Anti-Intellectualism in the Election of 1828" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 13, Folder 140)
    - Kline, Kathryn Flom. ""We Would Have No Flag but Religion and Fatherland": Contesting Religion, Revolution and Rural Modernization in 1920's Michoacan" Max Bildner Prize (Box 13, Folder 141)
    - Kurtz-Phelan, Daniel. "Que Se Vayan Todos: Economic Reform, Unemployment, and Popular Protest in Argentina" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 13, Folder 142)
    - Ladine, Bret. "Henry R. Luce and the Quest for Power, 1908-1923" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 13, Folder 143)
    - Rigo, Thomas. "A Horseman of the Apocalypse?: The Early Modern Postal System and the Plague" Andrew D. White Prize - European (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Schouten, Schuyler. "Kissinger's Realist Ethics: Morality and Pragmatism in American Foreign Policy" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 14, Folder 146)
    - Smith, Kumi (Margaret). "The 153 Japanese War Paintings: In Search of a New Identity" (Box 14, Folder 147)
    - Wolfram, Alice. ""Beare witness, I praye yow: she calls her whoare": Defamation, Social Networks and the Life Course in Early Modern England" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 14, Folder 149)
    - Zeck, Gregory. "Another Side of the Mountain: Hi Shi in America, 1910-1917" (Box 14, Folder 150)
- Student essays awarded the Richard Hegel Prize on topics related to New Haven, 2001-2003; Accession 2004-A-095
  Accession consists of student essays awarded or honorably mentioned for the Richard Hegel Prize for essays related to New Haven.
  - Essays, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2004; Accession 2005-A-026
  - Donnelly, Ceara, "Super Man of the Seventies: Henry Kissinger as Hero, 1968-1976", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Falik, Rebecca Cohen, "Beneficent Work Through Imperialistic Means", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fellows, David, ""The Poor Women Will Make A Howl" General Sherman & the Deportation of the Sweetwater & Roswell Mill Workers During the Atlanta Campaign of 1864", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ferraro, Mathew, "Going M.A.D. Morality, Strategy, and Mutual Destruction, 1957-1986", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gaffield, Scott, "Justice Not Done: The Hanging of Elizabeth Workman", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gray, Sarah, "Different Like Night and Day: Race & Music in Louisiana's Southwest Prairies", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Additional material - Different Like Night and Day [audio recordings], 412 (Box 2)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 1.7U)
  - Haviland, Jade, "Maya: Muslims & Myths of the Nation-State in India's 'National' Cinema", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Heiges, Moira, "From Island to Mainland & Back Again: Sociology & the Puerto Rican Family from 1930-1960", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Herbert, Maeve Elizabeth, "The Court Martial of Admiral John Byng, 1756-1757: A Critical Analysis of the Public's Response", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Joffe-Block, Judith, "Cultivating Sciences & Breeding Variety: Knowledge Cultures at Mexico's National School of Agriculture, 1924-200.", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kripke, "There Were Plenty Of Things to Do: The Hollywood Review's Struggle Against Blacklisting in the Motion Picture Industry in the 1950's", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kruger, Daniel, "Aspects of German Subversion in Ireland During the Second World War", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lambe, Ariel Mae, "To Work for the Good of the Majority of Men: The Intellectual Debate Between Nationalism & Socialism in Cuba", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Liotta, Erin: "Bill T. Jones & Uncle Tom: Understanding Modern America Through the Politics of Dance", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Munez, Ana Isabel, "A Narrowed Causa: the Mexican-American, and the Fall of Pan-Ethnic Unity in the United Farm Workers Union, 1965-1971", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Riviara, Matt, "First Impressions Count: The Literature of Advise on Office Design for the Urban American Physican, 1900-1930", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Shirane, Seiji, "Forming "Good Japanese People": National Ethics Textbooks in Imperial Japan, 1903-1945", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2005; Accession 2005-A-179
  - Ablavsky, Gregory. "Empire of Friends Quaker Travellers in the Eighteenth-Century Transatlantic World" John Addison Porter Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Bloom, Mathew. "A Distintegration of Morale: The Failure to Organize Black Workers at Winchester During World War II" Hegel New Haven History Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Brendan J. "The Role of Stage Magic in the Popularization of Victorian Science: Selling Science with Smoke and Mirrors" Andrew D. White Prize—European, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Theodore. "How Cuban Socialism Defined Latin America, 1959 to 1975: Creating the Latin American Caliban" Max Bildner Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Devlin, Mathew. "The Social Assimilation of Migrants in Early Modern England" Winifred Sturley Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Dietrich, Christian. "George Bird Grinnell, the Blackfeet Indians, and Glacier National Park" McClintock Award for Native American History, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Farber, Hannah. "The Eventful Careers of Two Agents of Sir Ferdinando Gorges, And How They Stole the Province of Lygonia from Him: The "Arrantest Known Knoves" of New England, 1627-1658" John Addison Porter Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Flores, Lori. "An Unladylike Strike Fashionably Clothed: Mexican American and Anglo Women Garment Workers Against Tex-Son, 1959-1963" Howard R. Lamar Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Fox, Margaret. "Old Testament Iconography in the Thirteenth-Century Windows of Bourges Cathedral: History, Allegory, and Christian Perceptions of the Jews" Andrew D. White Prize—European, 2005 (Box 1)
  - French, Kara. "The Women's Liberation Movement and the Rise of Feminist Neo-Paganism in America, 1975-1985: I Am Witch, Hear Me Roar" Edwin W. Small Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Hutt, Ethan. "The Language of Assimilation: A History of Bilingual Edication in New Haven, Connecticut, 1890-1920" Hegel New Haven History Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Kunakhovich, Kyrill. "The Pushkin Centennial of 1937: Russia Abroad, the Soviet Union, and the Politics of Russian National Identity" Wolfgang Leonhard Prize in Russian and East European Studies, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Massie, Caroline. "Japanese Diunity at the Rape of Nanking" Williams Prize in East Asian Studies, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Penner, Sydney. "Sixteenth-Century Swiss Anabaptists and the Miraculous: The Puzzle of Hasslibacher's Laughing Head" Andrew D. White Prize—European, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Perry, Avi. "The Jewish-Indian Theory and the Erosion of Religious Faith among Early American Christians" David Potter Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Reeve, Alexandra. "A Government of Men: Experimental Jurisprudence, Legal Realism and the New Deal" Percival W. Clement Prize, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Rice, Deanna. "Commemoration and Identity at the Whitehall Cenotaph and Scottish National War Memorial in the Context of National Historical Narrative" Winifred Sturley Prize, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Silber, Natasha. "The Wilmington Massacre and U. S. Imperialism: "Red Shirts," "Rough Riders," and the Politics of White Supremacy, 1898" Max Bildner Prize, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Walker, Rebecca E. "Courtship in 19th American Century Etiquette Manuals" Libby Gitlin Prize, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Zhang, Taisu. "Searching for Balance: Zhang Zhidong"s Comparisons of Chinese and Western Learning, 1898-1905" Robert D. Gries Prize, 2005 (Box 2)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2006; Accession 2006-A-206
  - Bustamante, Michael J. "Aristocratic Radicals: El Grupo Minorista and the Cuban Central Cultural Avant-Garde, 1923-1929" Max Bildner Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Michael C. "Holocaust Memory in Edgewood Park: Constructing the New Haven Memorial Tribute to the Six Million" American Jewish Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Butler, Stephen. "The St. Albans Raid of 1864: A Confederate Attack on Vermont and its Impact on the Confederation Debate in Canada" John Addison Porter Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chan, Michael. "China's Experiment with Representative Government, 1909-13" Andrew D. White Prize in R.O.W., 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chen, Jennifer. "The Chinese Divide: The Impact of Communism in China on New York's Chinese Community in the 1950s" Henry K. Havase-American Studies, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fine, Lauren. "Jewish Athletic and Social Clubs in Twentieth Century Buenos Aires: Creation, Formation and Isolation of the Argentine Jewish Community" American Jewish Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fishman, Peter. "The Student is a Citizen: Constructing Schooling Guatemala's Western Highlands, 1944-1954" Max Bildner Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Goodman, Jeffrey B. "The City of Oil and Water: The Rise and Fall of an American Landscape" Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gordley, Catherine. "Remembering Cesare Battisti: The Political Legacy of a Great War Martyr (1916-1919)" Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hardwick, Margery Thayer. "The National Literacy Crusade of 1980 and its Legacy in Adult Education in Nicaragua" Andrew D. White Prize in R.O.W., 2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kau, Andrew. "Genesis of a National Poet: Paradise Lost and English Cultural Politics, 1688-1701" Winifred Sturley Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lee, Alexander. "Crisis in Kerala: Congressmen, Communists and the Decline of Indian Federalism" Robert Gries D. Prize, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Leibenluft, Jacob. "Broken Promises and Missed Opportunities: How the Free Trade Consensus of the 1960s Collapsed" Percival Wood Clement, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Leiter, Richard. "Entre Deux Maisons: The Jewish Exodus from Montreal to Toronto in the 1970s," The Canadian Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lubin, Molly. "Empire, Politics, and Disease: The Divergence between British Doctors and Colonial Administrators in Nineteenth Century India Over the Cause and Prevention of Cholera" Andrew D. White Prize in R.O.W., 2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Marier, Virginie. "O Kennedy (We Stand On Guard For Thee): JFK in Cold War Canada" Edwin W. Small Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - McGill, Patrick. "Chasing Thucydides: Re-Imagining the Battle of Pylos (425BC)" Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 2006
    General
    See: oversize, box 3
  - Gregory, Mulvey. "The Nuclear Non-Proliferation Policy of the United States during the 1960s: Evaluating Nuclear Danger and Accepting the Unacceptable in a Decade of New Nuclear Weapons States" Percival Wood Clement, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Novitch, Julia. "'I can move no farther:' Representations of the Vanishing Indian in American Children's Literature From 1820-1860" The McClintock Prize-BRBL, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pudlin, Julia. "How the American Civil War Changed Mother and Daughter Roles in the White Southern Family: No Mother's Heart to Rest Upon" Libby Gitlin Prize, David Morris Potter Prize-BRBL, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Reid Amelia J. ""Ride Instead of Walk: Social Conflict between the Elite and the Gaucho During the Late Colonial and Early Independence Period in Argentina" Robert D. Gries Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rubin, Tamar Aliza. "The Story of Yellow Fever in Black and White: Race Relations in the Philadelphia Epidemic of 1793" John Addison Porter Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - West, Max. "The San Francisco Committee of Vigilance of 1851: Lynch Law and the Court of Public Opinion" The Lamar Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Winer, Rachel. "Diabetes, the National Institutes of Health, and the Arizona Pima Indians: A Study of Ethics and Experimentation in American Medicine, 1965 to the Present" Martin Klein and George Rosen Prize, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Oversize (Box 3)
    - McGill, Patrick. "Chasing Thucydides: Re-Imagining the Battle of Pylos (425BC)" Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 2006
- History senior essay prize winners, 2007; Accession 2007-A-202
  - Appleton, Alice Elizabeth, "Unity through Cultural Integration: New York City's Great Cigar Makers' Strike of 1877," John Addison Porter Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boehm, Josh, "Decoding de Gaulle: The United States and the French Recognition of Communist China in 1964," Andrew White Prize - European, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bressler, Jonathan, "The Red Badge of Infamy: John Punnett Peters and the Fate of the Federal Employment Loyalty Program," Andrew White Prize - American, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Counts, Lindsey, " Popular Politics and the Published Petition in the English Civil Wars," Winifred Sturkey Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Courtney, Jocelyn Joan, "The Civil War that Was Fought by Children: Understanding the Role of Child Combatants in El Salvador's Civil War 1980-1992" Andrew White Prize - Rest of the World, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Derusha, David J., "The Committees of Correspondence in Massachusetts and Virginia, 1772-1774: Engine of Ideology," Andrew White Prize - American, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ellis, Jordan, " The People's Planet: Reactions to the Discovery of Pluto," Martin Klein & George Rosen Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Feinstein, Eric, "The Development of United States Cultural Diplomacy: Chester Bowles in India, 1951-1953," John Addison Porter Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fine, Eve, "The Bookbinder and the Sexologist: Rubin Bresler, Alfred Kinsey, and the Institute for Sex Research Library," Edwin W. Small Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Franke, Tiffany, "From Paternalism to Protest: Labor Relations in a Southern Textile Mill Community," Andrew White Prize - American, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Frick, Ali, "The Mingled Dust of Both Armies: Yale's Compromised Civil War Memorial," David M. Potter Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gabbard, Matt, "Lord Robert Cecil and the League of Nations: Colelctive Security in the 1920s and 1930s," The Canadian Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Giller, Gillian, "Justice Potter Strewart and the Rise and Fall of the Reporter's Privilege," Percival Wood Clement Prize, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Greer, Laura J., "Of Her Time and Ahead of Her Time: Early Childhood Education Pioneer Abigail Adams Eliot," Libby Gitlin Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Kellert, Raquel, "British Colonial Education in Bengal, 1770-1835: Evangelical Anglicism's Divergent Affects on Hindus and Muslims," Andrew White Prize - Rest of the World, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Kolkin, Thomas P., "Huron Lacrosse in the Seventeenth and Eighteenth Centuries: An Examination of Notions of Sport, Ritual, and Culture in Indian Communities," The Walter McClintock Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Landau, Micah, " The Postmodern Rebellion? Chiapas, Marcos, and the EZLN," Max Bildner Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lewis, Dain, "The Developer's Game: The Private Sector and the Church Street Project, 1955-1964," The Richard Hegel Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Lie, Han Liang, "John Locke's Social Considerations in the 1696 Recoinage Controversy: Discovering English Coin and Recoinage in their Social Context," Winifred Sturley Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Logan, Alison M. B., "A Museum of Ideas: Evolution Education at the Peabody Museum during the 1920s," Martin Klein & George Rosen Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mathias, Christine Joy, "At the Edges of Empire: Race and Revolution in the Mexican Border Town of Cananea, 1899-1917," Andrew White Prize - Rest of the World, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Porter, Karen, "America and the Armenians 1915-1921: Principle, Power and the Making of U.S. "Humanitarian" Foreign Policy," Edwin W. Small Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ruggeri, Amanda, "The Indian Mutiny Narrative: Gender, Politics and the British Press in the Fashioning of an Imperial Relationship, circa 1857-1891," Andrew White Prize - European, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Samel, Rebecca, "Count Folke Bernadotte: From Holocaust Hero to Forgotten Martyr," The Jewish American Congress Prize in Judaic Studies, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sandberg-Zakian, Eric, "Misinterpreting Intelligence: Jeffersonian Republicanism and the Frontier Crisis of 1807-1812," John Addison Porter Prize; Howard Lamar Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Saylor, Joshua K., "Inundation of a World," The Walter McClintock Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Tan, Carolyn, "The Maitatsine Movement 1980-1985: Religion, Violence, and Social Discontent in North Nigeria," Robert D. Gries Prize, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2008; Accession 2008-A-169
  - Alaghband, Mina, "Geoffrey Elton: Identity in Practice ," Winifred Sturley Prize - European, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibler, Zena, "La Revancha del Tango: Tango and the Search for Argentine Identity," Andrew White Prize - Rest of the World, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bonvillian, Raphael, "Caught in the Middle: An American Perspective on Ethnic Responses to Chinese and Soviet Influence in Xinjiang, 1944-1951," Andrew White Prize - Rest of the World, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bospflug, Elizabeth, "The Mountain Republic of the North Caucasus and Dagestan, 1917-1919: Ill-Fated Nationalist Liberalism in an Era of Extremes," Andrew White Prize - European, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cassis, Brady, "The Tumultuous Road to 'Thatcherism': The Transformation of Britain's Tories, 1974-1979," Winifred Sturley Prize - European, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chaloff, Scott, "Dynamite Tonight: Vietnam On and Off-Stage at the Yale School of Drama, 1966-1969," John Addison Porter Prize, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fitzgerald, Maura, "Second Line Parades in New Orleans: Revelry and Resistance in the 'Spaces Between'," Andrew White Prize - American, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Fowler, Stephen, "Crisis and Compromise: Carter Glass, Henry Steagall, and the Story of the Banking Act of 1933," Percival Clement Prize, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hale, Natalie Adele, "Chivalry and Health: The Modern Health Crusade, Antimodernism, Children's Health, and the Cultural Politics of Early 20th Century America," Edwin Small Prize - American, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Henry, Lauren, "African American Hip-Hop and South Africa: Identity, Community and Multicultural Appropriation," Robert D. Gries Prize, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ickes, Charlotte, "The Kneeling Slave: Race and the Visual Imagination of the Nineteenth Century," George Washington Egleston Prize, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kleiner, Alexander Mark, "The Wind That Swept Rivera: The Battle of Rockefeller Center and the Meaning of His American Tour, 1930-1940", 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Linzer, Katherine, "Sesame Street in the Community, 1966-1974: Can Television Educate Low-Income Children?," Edwin Small Prize - American, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Lopez Fadul, Valeria Escauriaza, "The Wavering Fortune of the Cosmography and Geography of Africa, 1526-2006," Andrew White Prize - European, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - MacLeod, Jessie, "'A trial incident to the calling of a missionary': The Decision of Nineteenth-Century American Missionaries to Send Their Children Home," George Washington Egleston Prize, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pitts, Freya, "Fighting Like a Lady: Resistance and Femininity in Memoirs of Occupied France," Andrew White Prize - European, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Scholz, Max, "Thomas Müntzer in Mülhausen: How Communism Resurrected a Reformation Radical," Andrew White Prize - European, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Vanderbilt, Sarah, "Equal Partners in Peace: The Long Shadow of World War I Women's Activism, 1915-1950," John Addison Porter Prize, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2009; Accession 2010-A-012
  - American Prizes, 2009
    - The Percival Wood Clement Prize in American History, 2009
      - Nicholas Aaron Handler, "Respectability and Radicalism: Harry Weinberger, the Jewish Left, and the Fight for Free Speech"; advisor: Professor Jennifer Klein, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The John Addison Porter Prize in American History, 2009
      - Nikolas Bowie, "Class Warfare, Inc.: James L. Buckley and the Conservative Origins of Corporate Class Consciousness in the 1970s"; advisor: Professor Jennifer Klein, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Brooks Tucker Swett, "Transatlantic Confederates: British Aristocratic Support for the South in the Civil War"; advisor: David Blight, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Andrew D. White Prize in American History, 2009
      - Anna Legant Parks, "Polio Across the Iron Curtain:Dorothy M. Horstmann's 1959 Evaluation of the Sabin 'Polio Vaccine Trial in the U.S.S.R."; advisor: Professor Bruno Strasser, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Genna Michelle Braverman, "Philadelphia Public Housing and the Participatory Mandate: The City Politics of the War on Poverty"; advisor: Professor Jennifer Klein, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Lee Juliana Glandorf, "Recipe for Reunion: The Women's Executive Centennial Committee of the 1876 International Exhibition and the Creation of the National Cookery Book"; advisor: Professor Glenda Gilmore, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Sarah Hadassah Mishkin, "Investing in Peace: Thomas W. Lamont and the Stabilization of Europe after the First World War"; advisor: Professor Beverly Gage, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Edwin W. Small Prize in American History, 2009
      - Margaret Vivian Goodlander, "THE PITFALLS OF RIVALRY: Foreign Policy Rivalry in the Carter Administration and Its Meaning for U.S. Policy in Iran"; advisor: Professor John Lewis Gaddis, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Mariana Elise Brandman, "The Voice of Feminist Wit in the Women's Suffrage Movement: Examining Alice Duer Miller's "Are Women People?"; advisor: Professor Beverly Gage, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - European Prizes, 2009
    - The Andrew D. White Prize in European History, 2009
      - Kevin Eric Levenberg, "Living Propaganda, Living Witnesses: Soviet Prisoners of War through the Eyes of Germans, 1941-1943"; advisor: Professor Timothy D. Snyder, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Winifred Sturley Prize in European History, 2009
      - Elisabeth Mariko Leake, "Empire on the Brink: The. Indian Army and the North West Frontier in British Policy and the Coming of the Second World War"; advisor: Professor Paul M. Kennedy, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Tanya Michaela Whisnant, "Culture and Commerce: The Role of Phoenicians in Eighteenth Century British Histories as Related to Defining National Identity"; advisor: Professor Steven Pincus, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Rest of the World Prizes, 2009
    - The Andrew D. White Prize in Rest of the World History, 2009
      - Katharine Anne Kendrick, "Airwaves to the Arab World: U.S. Public Diplomacy Broadcasting in the Middle East"; advisor: Professor Patrick Cohrs, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Robert E Gries Rest of the World History, 2009
      - Christina Allderdice Pryor, "'The Real, Bleeding Vietnam': Bernard Fall on the Street without Joy, 1953-1967"; advisor: Professor Benedict Kiernan, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Max Bildner Prize in Latin American History, 2009
      - Matthew Benjamin Eisenson, "The Myth of Pacifism, The Reality of Politics: The Roots and Consequences of Unilateral Demilitarization in Costa Rica"; advisor: Professor Gilbert Joseph, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - History of Science/History of Medicine Prize, 2009
    - Martin Klein and George Rosen Prize, 2009